A Guide to the Walther and Hertha Riese papers, 1898-1975
Virginia Commonwealth University
- Series 5: Subject Files
  - Brains: Rabbit, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Brown-Sequard, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Central Nervous System, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Central Nervous System: Gooddy (author), 1957 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Cerebral Ageing in Prominent Scientists, undated (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Cerebral Hemorrhage: Teaching Material, undated (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Certificate: American Geriatric Society, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Chronic Alcoholism, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Clicnial Lecture Notes, undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Clinical Notes: Abstract, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Contracts (building) for House, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Demyelinating Diseases, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Edinger Brain (see also Oversized), undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1958-1968 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Euthanasia, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Euthanasia and Medical Ethics, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Fifth Book of Special Physiology, undated (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Franklin, Benjamin, undated (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Freud, Sigmund, undated (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Goethe University, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Greco-Arab Medicine, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Haymakers' Paper, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Hemorrhage, Atrophy, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Historiograph- compilation of authors' works, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - History of Medicine Course, 1950 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - History of Neurology, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - History of Treatment of Insanity, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Huntington's Chorea, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 9- 10)
  - Instinct, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - International Congress of Neuropathology, 1949, 1951, 1955, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 12-16)
  - International Congress of Neuropathology, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Israel: Correspondence regarding, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Israel Information Services, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Law Suit Consult, 1958-1961 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Lifwynn Foundation, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Mariage et Troubles Mentales, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Medical College of Virginia, undated (Box 35, Folder 7-9)
  - Marchiafava-Bignaimi's Disease, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Metastic Tumors, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Monakow, CV (see also oversize), 1951 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Monakow's Case Eich II, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Muller, Johannes (see also oversized material), undated (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Muller, Johannes, 1896, circa 1966, undated (Box 40, Folder 1, 8-9)
  - Naar's Story "The Italian" (Naar- Psychiatrist for the City), undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - National Institute of Health, undated (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - National Science Foundation, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Nervous Diseases: Classic Description, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Neuropathology Juniors (students), 1951 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Neuropathology Teaching Material, 1949 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Nursing Care of Neurological Patients, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - N.Y. Ontoanalytic Association, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Peptic Ulcer, 1950 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Philosophy: Heinroth, Ideler, Langermann, undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Philosophy: Hippocrates and Galen, undated (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy: Ideler on Langermann and Stahl, undated (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy: Kielmeyer on Evolution of Thought, undated (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, Riese, undated (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Richmond, City of, Contract, undated (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Richmond Research Council, undated (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Riese: CV, personal info, financial info, 1959-1973, undated (Box 36, Folder 17-20)
    Restricted?
  - Sanders-Benson, undated (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Schlatter and Roth notes, 1912-1913, 1930, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Semmelweiss Hospital, undated (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Societe Internationale de Psychopathologie, 1967, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 23-24)
  - Springer, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Stocks/Checkbook, 1958-1960 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Teaching Lectures, undated (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - University of California Press, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Van Helmont, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Ventricle Cysts, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Vesalius, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Veterans' Administrative Lectures, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (RPI), 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 8-9)
  - Virginia Dabney, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation- Correspondence, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Wiedergatmaching: Correspondence, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Wisdom of the Ancients, undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - World Congress of Psychiatry, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Zurich Conference, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 15)
- Series 6: Research Grants
  - Research Grants, 1954-1962 (Box 38, Folder 1-9)
  - Research Grants, 1962-1967 (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
  - HEW-NIH Publications, 1954-1957 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Research Grant Applications, 1959-1967 (Box 39, Folder 5-7, 11-13)
  - NIH History of Medicine Commitee Guidelines, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 8-9)
  - Research Grant Awards, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - NIH History of Medicine Study Section, 1962 (Box 39)
- Series 7: Publications
  Publications in Series 7 can be searched in the VCU Libraries catalog using the "Walther Riese Collection" search term.